- Quack, quack. - Look out!
- کواک, کواک. - مه کوري!
He singed my tail feathers.
يکار ميکني الاغ
Yee-ha!
يو هو
All right, Buzz. That's enough of that.
خيله خب،الان هري بخوام برميدارم
What did I just say?
خب حالا بايد يکار کنيم؟
That is a good way to lose an eye, my friend.
الان يه راه رديف يدا ميکنم دوست عزيزم
Hold it. We've got company at two o'clock.
آماده..بايد تا دو ساعت ديه اونجا باشيم
I got him, Mailman. Hang on.
آماده ام رفيق ..حالا بزن بريم
Here we go.
ببين ه ميکنه
- Buzz, what is goin' on up there? - Just movin' a road hog.
اون جاده يه اون ايين..؟ از اين جاده کلي راز و خوک رد ميشن
- Knock it off! What kind of stunt was that? - Just seein' what this baby can do.
اي خاک بر سر اين الاغ بکنن با اين کاراي مسخره ش عين اين به ها مي مونه بيشعور
This bag of bones isn't rated past Mach two.
اين اسباب بازي واسه بيشتر از دو "ماخ" سرعت طراحي نشده ها
- Mach one! - The G-forces, Buzz! The G-forces!
"يک "ماخ همه ي قاطي کرده،داره هشدار ميده
Mach two! Gotta push the envelope.
حالا دو "ماخ"..بايد اونو فشار بدي
Mach three!
"واي حالا سه "ماخ
Buzz! We're tearing apart!
اوه..داريم از هم مي اشيم
I'm losin' control. Eject, Mailman. Hit the silk!
کنترل از دستم در رفته ديه بايد ايجکت کنيم شاسکول
- I can't get out! - What are you doing?
مال من باز نميشه داري يکار ميکني؟
Buzz! Get back here!
کجا رفتي نامرد..بررد
OK. I've been in tougher scrapes than this.
خيله خب..خونسرد باش سر..ممکنه فقط يه کم منفجر بشي
There's the ground. It looks hard. OK, trees.
دارم ميرسم به زمين،الان منفجر ميشم حالا دارم ميرم تو جنل
No! Oh. Mahogany. Ow!
نه..اوه..واي..ه وب کلفتي
Squirrel's nest. Bird. Ow! Pine.
درخت کاجم هست..اوه..لانه سنجاب..رنده،اوه
Ow! Oh, the ground.
اوه..نه..رسيدم زمين
Oh... Oh...
اوه... اوه...
Oh, I made it.
بالاخره تموم شد
I made it! There is a God.
نفتم ميتونم خدا هميشه با منه
Hallelujaaaaaa!
نوکرتم خدا
Ow! Oh! Ouch! Ow!
اويي! اوه! آخ! اويي!
Oh, you're French, aren't you?
تو اهل فرانسه بودي ديه نه؟
Ah... yeah, just like that.
بله،ولي نه فقط يه کم بودم
- Hey, look! There's one! - Uh-oh.
اونجا رو ببين..يه وزن،بزنش
Topper Harley?
آقاي "تار" شمايين؟
Once, perhaps.
يه زماني شايد
Now I am called Tukachinchilla.
"ولي الان بهم مين "توکاين يلا
- What does it mean? - Fluffy Bunny Feet.
خوب حالا يعني ي؟ يعني يه آدم عزلت نشين
It's very nice.
قدر خوب
I'm Lieutenant Commander James Block.
من ستوان "جيمز بلاک" فرمانده هوانيروزم
I knew your father Buzz.
درتو خيلي خوب ميشناختم
Until his incident, he was the greatest pilot who ever lived.
تا زمانيکه اون حادثه دلخراش اتفاق افتاد خلبان بي نظيري بود
We need to talk.
ميشه داخل حرف بزنيم
The Navy wants...
..نيروي دريايي قصد داره که
The Navy wants you back, Harley.
نيروي دريايي قصد داره که تورو دوباره برردونه
They threw me out. Why should I go back?
مثه وسفند رتم کردن بيرون را بايد برردم؟
I came here to get away from the Navy. Away from flying.
اومدم اينجا تا از نيروي دريايي دور باشم همنين رواز کردن
The Navy has a top-secret mission: Sleepy Weasel.
نيروي دريايي يه مأموريت سري بنام "راسوي خفته" داره
I'm giving you a second chance, which your father never had.
ميخوام يه شانس ديه بهت بدم که درت از اين شانس محروم شد
You're the best of the best, Topper.
تو يکي از بهترين نيروهاي ما بودي
Leave me to speak with the one. He is wise in the ways of such things.
قبل از همه ي بايد با اون مشورت کنم
The Navy really needs you.
ولي اونجا خيلي بهت نياز دارن
Great helium!
عجب بالني بود ممنون
Owatonna.
"اوتانا"
Every night I hope and pray
Every night I hope and pray
A dream lover will come my way
A dream lover will come my way
A girl to hold in my arms
A girl to hold in my arms
And know the magic of her charms
And know the magic of her charms
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- A girl
- A girl
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
I want a dream lover
I want a dream lover
I don't have to dream alone
I don't have to dream alone
Dream lover, until then
Dream lover, until then
I'll go to sleep, I'll dream again
I'll go to sleep, I'll dream again
That's the only thing to do
That's the only thing to do
Till all my lover's dreams come true
Till all my lover's dreams come true
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- A girl
- A girl
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
I want a dream lover
I want a dream lover
I don't have to dream alone
I don't have to dream alone
Dream lover, until then
Dream lover, until then
I'll go to sleep, I'll dream again
I'll go to sleep, I'll dream again
That's the only thing to do
That's the only thing to do
Till all my lover's dreams come true
Till all my lover's dreams come true
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- A girl
- A girl
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
I want a dream lover
I want a dream lover
I don't have to dream alone
I don't have to dream alone
Wow!
واي!
Wha-hoo!
يو هو!
Ten... hut!
روهان خبردار
Admiral. Good to see you again, sir.
قربان،واقعاً از ديدنتون خوشحالم
- It's been too long. - And so it has. Yes, yes.
خيلي وقته نديدمتون منم خوشحالم ،سرهن بودي ديه
- How are ya, sir? - Hawaii?
حالتون طوره قربان؟ هاوايي..؟
- Goddamn it, Bill, I should be in California. - No, sir, this is California.
"لعنت به تو "بيل"،ميخواستم برم "کاليفرنيا نه قربان،اينجا "کاليفرنيا"ست
- Well, gotta run. Good luck. - But, sir, this is your command.
خب،س موفق باشين ديه ولي قربان ما به دستور شما اينجاييم
Sleepy Weasel has been planned for ten months. The president hand-picked you.
همون عمليات سري "راسوي خفته" ديه قربان و افرادي که بايد انتخاب ميشدن
Damn right he did. No stoppin' us now, huh, Ted?
اوه راست ميي سر؟ س را منتظزي "تد"؟
I'll show you your offices and brief you.
شمارو تا دفتر کارتون راهنمايي ميکنم
You're a fine soldier, Scott. Lead the way.
تو واقعاً يه نيروي خوب و وظيفه شناسي
Oh, good God. I gotta pee.
اوه،عجب شانسي..بايد برم دستشويي
I had part of my bladder blown off at Guadalcanal.
آخه يه بخشي از مثانه من به کلي از بين رفته
Watch your step. There's a lot of obstructions here.
س مراقب باشين ممکنه دار انسداد مثانه بشين
- I had a little dreidel! - I made it out of clay!
- I had a little dreidel! - I made it out of clay!
- And when it's dry and ready... - My dreidel I will play!
- And when it's dry and ready... - My dreidel I will play!
- Here's the story... - Of a lovely lady!
- Here's the story... - Of a lovely lady!
- Who was bringing up... - Three very lovely girls!
- Who was bringing up... - Three very lovely girls!
- All of them had hair of gold! - Like their mother!
- All of them had hair of gold! - Like their mother!
- The youngest one... - In curls!
- The youngest one... - In curls!
- Here's the story... - Of a man named Brady!
- Here's the story... - Of a man named Brady!
Gentlemen, he's back.
به ها من برشتم
How ya been?
طوري سر..؟
- Yeah, it's the big guy. - Good to see ya.
تو طوري رفيق؟ مي بينم که همه ي رديفه
- Scooter! How you doin'? - Topper. The main man.
تو طوري "اسکوتر"؟ هي..بزن ببينم رفيق
- Rabbi! Mazel tov. - You should live and be well!
تو طوري "خاخام"؟ معلومه خوب بهتون ساخته
Hey, buddy.
سلام رفيق
Are you OK?
حالت خوبه؟
You don't look so hot. You need some help?
به نظر که خوب نيستي کمک نميخواي؟
I'm OK.
من خوبم
You're Topper Harley, aren't you?
تو "تار" نيستي؟
I hear you've got chops we only dream of. Throwin' you out was a bum rap.
دربارت زياد شنيده بودم البته هرکسي يه يزي ميفت ديه
I'm Jim Pfaffenbach. Everybody calls me Wash Out.
من "جيم فافنبا"ام مثه آدم نميتونم دست بدم
- You're a pilot? - Oh, yeah. I'm gonna be flyin' with ya.
تو هم خلباني؟ اوه،آره..عاشق رواز کردنم
Good.
خوبه
Cute.
عاليه
I like to stay in shape. Thanks.
دوست دارم هميشه باهام باشن..ممنونم
- Are these all at home? - Yeah.
عکس کل خونواده ديه..آره؟ آره
The dogs, wife and kids.
همسر..به ام با دوتا سم
You got pictures of your family, I'd love to see 'em.
تو ي عکسي از خونوادت نداري دوست دارم ببينمشون
- I am my family photo. - But everybody needs a family to love.
فعلاً که خودم يه خونواده ام ولي همه نياز به يه عشق دارن واسه زندي
I could never find time for love. It's too heavy.
تا حالا که نتونستم يداش کنم..يعني سخته
It's an anchor that drowns a man.
الانم مثل يه آدم غرق شده ام
Besides, I got the sky, the smell of jet exhaust, my bike.
تازه،من که تو آسمونم هميشه تنها دلخوشيمم شده صداي موتور جت
- A loner? - No. I own it.
يه آدم انزواطلب!!..نه،اينجوري راحتترم
I can see I'm gonna have to work on you.
در هر صورت همه جوره در خدمتم
Name's Pete Thompson. But...
اسم اصليم "يت تامسون"..ولي
...everybody calls me Dead Meat.
"همه بهم مين "وشت مرده
- Topper Harley. - Just a pleasure.
منم "تار "ام خوشبختم
Attention on deck!
آسايشاه بجاي خود
Good morning, sir!
صبح بخير قربان
I don't care how many missions you've flown!
اصلاً واسم مهم نيست که تا حالا در ه مآموريتي رواز کرده باشين
I don't care how good you think you are! You're nobody!
اهميت نميدم که دارم با کدوم خري حرف ميزنم به هيکس اهميت نميدم
And for the next ten days, nobody takes a crap unless I say so!
و تا ده روز آينده هيکس کاري نميکنه مر اينکه من دستور داده باشم
- Got it? - Yes, sir!
افتاد..؟ بله قربان
I said "Attention".
نرفتي ي فتم
Now, didn't I make myself clear? Or don't you take orders?
کجاي حرفايي که زدم روشن نبود نميدوني اجراي يه دستور يعني ي؟
- When I say "Attention", I mean "Attention". - Yes, sir!
وقتي ميم توجه کنين يعني بايد توجه کنين بله قربان
Now!
همين الان
- You eyeballin' me, mister? - No, sir!
واسه توام بايد توضيح بدم سرکار؟ نه قربان
The next time I see that ugly face of yours,
دوباره نببينم با اين ريختو قيافه اينجا باشي يه ذره مو روي بدنت ببينم واي بحالت
I want it clean-shaven! Suck in that chest!
من مي خوام تمامشو برتراشي! يه جور که بشه سينه رو خورد!
Pfaffenbach!
"فافنبا"
- What you lookin' at, boy? - Nothin', sir!
دنبال ي داري ميردي؟ هيي قربان
Oh, I'm some lowlife that's not good enough for you to talk to?
با اين حال و روزم فکر نکنم که ديه بايد واسه توام توضيح بدم ها
Well, that attitude is short on collateral! I'm God as far as you're concerned!
اين رفتارت اصلاً ذيرفتني نيست واسم تا وقتي که من اينجام بي نظمي معني نداره
Hey, hey. Lighten up.
خب فهميديم ديه
Cut the kid some slack.
عالم و آدم فهميدن ديه
Who the hell are you talkin' to, son?
کي به تو اجازه داد که حرف بزني سرجون؟
Your ego's writin' cheques your body can't cash.
هروقت فتن خاک انداز اونوقت خودتو جلو بنداز
Now you got five minutes to stow your gear.
از همين الانم نج دقيقه بيشتر وقت ندارين
Get movin'!
س بجُنبين
Yeah, I'm sure deep down he means well.
آره،من مطمئنم که باطناً آدم خوبيه
I hope you were paying attention.
اميدوارم خوب متوجه شده باشي که ي فت
- I don't think we've met. - Kent Gregory.
فکر نميکنم تا حالا ديده باشمت "کنت روري"
Excuse me if I don't shake your hand.
ببخشيد که باهات دست نميدم
Your father killed someone very special to me: Dominic "Mailman" Farnham.
درت باعث کشته يکي از بهترين افراد زنديم شد "دومنيک فارنهام"
- You mean... - Yes.
..منظورت درسته
Dominic Farnham was my father. I was his love child.
دومنيک فارنهام" درم بود..منو خيلي دوست داشت"
- It was a hunting accident. - Accident, my deep-blue eyes.
اين يه اتفاق بود "در مأموريت "شم آبي عميق من
It was reckless, irresponsible flying, and you know it.
اين رواز هم ناشيانه بود هم غير مسئولانه و خودتم اينو ميدوني
Are you OK?
حالت خوبه؟
This is an incredible coincidence,
اين يه حادثه يشبيني نشده بود
but the hunter who mistakenly killed your father
که اون شکاري اشتباهاً به درت شليک کرده
was Henry Pfaffenbach, my father.
هنري فافنبا" درم بود"
I feel terrible.
لحظات خيلي سختي رو شت سر ذاشته بود
Isn't this Henry Alva Pfaffenbach?
اين همون "هنري آلوا فافنبا" نيست؟
My mother was a Pfaffenbach.
و اينم مادرم "فافنبا" که
Not... Doreen Pfaffenbach?
يعني "دورين فافنبا"..؟ آره
- From Minnesota? - Yeah.
اهل "مينه سوتا"..؟
Then we're cousins! We used to spend our summers in Eagle River.
س ما باهم فاميليم که..تعطيلات تابستوني در رودخونه عقاب بوديم
Eagle River?
رودخونه عقاب..؟
I hope you can forgive me for this.
اميدوارم منو بابت يه نين اتفاقي ببخشين
If it helps, I didn't have seconds.
تا ميتونم از کمکي دريغ نميکنم
That's all right. It's not your fault. Anyone could have made that mistake.
بسيار خب،ميدونم که شما هي تقصيري نداشتين هرکسي ممکنه در زنديش اشتباه بکنه
But him... he's the type that could end up killing every man in this outfit.
اما اين،با کارش ممکنه باعث کشته شدن خيلي از آدما بشه
Wait a minute. Why are you mad at me? He's the one who ate your father.
صبر کن ببينم..ميفهمي داري ي ميي؟ مه نديدي خودش اعتراف کرد که ي شده
Like father, like son. You've already been tossed out once.
مثل در و سر يادت باشه تو يه بار قبلاً سقوط کردي
Hold it, hold it.
صبر کنين ببينم..صبر کنين
We can't fight among ourselves. We're all on the same team here.
درست نيست خودمون به جون هم بيفتيم اينجا همه باهم دوستيم نه دشمن
I want the two of you to shake hands.
الانم ميخوام که باهم دست بدين تمومش کنين
There, now. Isn't that better?
همين الان اينجوري بهتر نيست؟
- Yeah. - Sure.
آره مطمئناً
There. We're friends again.
خوبه..بايد باهم رفيق باشيم ديه
Here. Have some of my lucky gum.
اين آدامس هميشه واسم شانس مياره
Look, Dead Meat. We fly together, we sleep next to each other, but that's all.
ببين"وشت مرده"،درسته که باهم رواز ميکنيم باهم ميخوابيم ولي اين دليل نميشه که
Don't get too close. Let me handle my own affairs.
ولي با اين آدم نميتونم کنار بيام س تو کار من دخالت نکن لطفاً
He's so complex.
آدم خيلي ييده ايه واقعاً
Aerial photos and recon reports indicate a defensive arsenal
هرکدوم از اين عکساي هوايي يه زرادخانه تسليحاتي رو نشون ميده
in the D, and perhaps -C, categories.
بخش دو يا شايدم بخش سوم
There's also some anti-aircraft squadrons.
در اينجا حتي يه تعداد ضدهوايي هم وجود داره
They can send up an ack-ack umbrella high enough to make any attack ineffective.
با استفاده از حربه تر دفاعي عملاً ميشه اونارو از کار انداخت
I don't have a clue what you're talkin' about, Phil.
ولي اين يزي که داري ميي يه کم بعيد به نظر ميرسه
I have a shell the size of a fist in my head Pork Chop Hill.
من يه غده داخل سرم دارم که وقتي تکون بخوره بايد سرمو بکوبم به يه جايي
The only way I can make this toup stay on
اين تنها راهيه که ميتونم کنترلش کنم
is by magnetising the upper left quadrant of my skull.
انار يه مغناطيس ر قدرت يک هارم جمجمه منو در اختيار رفته
You just go ahead and do what you do. Do you have any soup?
ولي تو يادت باشه که کار اصليتو انجام بدي راستي اينجا سو دارين؟
Of course, sir. I'll have the mess bring something right up.
البته قربان،بعضي از به ها اهي اوقات با خودشون ميارن
I love soup. I mean, I think I love soup.
عاشق سوم..يعني فکر ميکنم که عاشق سو باشم
Son-of-a-bitchin' shell. It's either soup or duck. Which one do you shoot?
لعنتي باز داره تکون ميخوره حالا ه سوي دارين؟سو اردک
Duck, sir.
اردک قربان
- Are you all right, sir? - Of course I'm all right.
حالتون خوبه قربان؟ آره خوبم مشکلي نيست
Why? What have you heard?
را رسيدي؟يزي شده؟
Nothing, sir.
يزي نيست قربان
Send some soup up for the admiral, on the double.
لطفاً بو دوتا سو مخصوص واسه آدميرال بيارن
Let's go over this Slippery Weevil one more time.
باز مثه يه خرطوم از جاش تکون خورد
I wanna familiarise myself with it as much
ميخوام خودم منم از همه ي سر دربيارم س هري که لازمه رو بايد بهم بي
as I possibly can. So... give it to me, Ben.
بنابراين هر ي بدرد بخور هست رو به من بده بن
Every word. Every detail.
با همه جزئيات و کلمات
Dot every comma.
حتي يه نقطه يا کاما
Those are some long legs.
ه اهاي بلند و کشيده اي دارين
I just had them lengthened. Now they go all the way up.
من فقط يه کم کشيدمشون ورنه که الان خودشون دارن کش ميارن
Wow.
..محشره
It's nice to see you again.
قدر خوب شد که دوباره ديدمتون..
I was really impressed, the way you handled that stallion.
من واقعاً اون روز خيلي تحت تأثير کارتون قرار رفتم
When I saw you dig your heels into his sides
اونم وقتي که ميديم طوري
tighten the reins and break his spirit,
آفتا مهتاب ميزدين اونم مثه آب خوردن
I never wanted to be a horse so much in my life.
هميشه آرزو داشتم که يه اسب داشته باشم
After I finish off this shrink, we can take a quick canter in the meadow.
بعد از اينکه کارتون تموم شد ميشه بريم يه قدمي بزنيم
Lieutenant, I am the shrink.
فعلاً که کار دارم ستوان
- You're the psychiatrist? - That's what the diploma says.
شما روانشناسين؟ اين مدارک که ميه هستم
I've never been to a psychiatrist before. You will be gentle?
تا حالا يش يه روانشناس نرفته بودم شما که ترسناک به نظر نميرسين
I've been ordered to review your records.
درباره ذشته تون يه يزايي به من فته شده
You were discharged from the service 18 months ago for wilful insubordination.
به مدت 18 ماه شمارو بخاطر سريي از دستور معلق کرده بودن
You disobeyed a direct order and lost a $13m fighter in the process.
سريي از دستور و سرعت بسيار زياد از بين بردن يه جننده و رداخت غرامت
Yes, I did. But I'm payin' it off at ten bucks a week.
درسته ولي با هفته اي ده دلار درآمد که نميتونم رداخت کنم
I should have gotten that extra collision coverage.
تازه اين حادثه فقط يه تصادف بوده و هي عمدي در کار نبوده
Wasn't your father involved in a similar incident?
واسه درتم دقيقاً يه نين حادثه اي يش اومده بود درسته؟
- What do you mean? - Leland "Buzz" Harley.
منظورتو نميفهمم؟ "ليلاند تار"
Three Purple Hearts, presidential commendation.
رئيس جمهور بابت تقدير ازون سه تا قلب بنفش بهش داده
Then this incident, the Dominic Farnham death.
حتي اين حادثه باعث مر "دومينيک فارنهام" هم شده
1971, his Visa card was cancelled.
سال 1971 ويزاش باطل شده
1975, a broken man,
سال 1975 وقتي از همه جا مونده
suffocated while working the night shift in a Fotomat booth.
و رونده شده بود در يه دکه شبانه روزي مشغول ميشه
Tell me how these events affected you.
ميخوام بدونم اين مسائل ه تأثيري روي تو ذاشته
Well, I... I don't think about it much.
خب،راستش تأثير زيادي در عملکرد و رفتارم نداشته
That was a long time ago.
ون مربوط به خيلي وقت يش ميشه.
Now if you'll excuse me, I have some guns to grease.
منو بابت اين تش قلبم بايد ببخشي ديه
Lieutenant...
ستوان
Have you thought about seeing a psychiatrist on a regular basis?
نظرتون درباره ملاقات و ديدار با يه روانزشک اونم بصورت منظم يه؟
I thought you'd never ask.
واسه ي اينو ميرسين
I mean professionally.
که بصورت جدي ادامش بدين
Thanks, Doctor.
ممنون دکتر
Thanks for the advice.
از راهنماييتونم ممنونم
- Be careful out there. - I can take care of myself.
مراقب خودتون باشين من نه کُسخلم نه رواني
- No. You're going to get hurt. - I don't need your help, or anybody's.
شما با اين کاراتون دارين بيشتر بهم آسيب ميزنين به کمک هيکسي نياز ندارم
I'll be just fine.
من کاملاً سالمم و مشکليم ندارم
Are you OK?
حالتون خوبه؟
Yeah. I'm fine.
آره خيلي خوبم
Oh...
اوه
Attention on deck.
لطفاً بلند شين به ها
At ease, men.
شروع کنين
Be seated.
حالا بشينين
Many of you are wondering about my pants.
ميدونم که با ديدن اين تيم دارين شاخ درميارين ولي بخاطر اينکه خاکي نشه کمه وشيدم
Well, they ran short of material at the knee.
خوب  زمان فرار کردن جلوي دست و اي آدم رو نمييره
So don't give me any shit.
س جون مادرتون رو من زوم نکنين
Now, I look out there at all of you guys and I say to myself:
الانم دوست دارم که يه صحبت دوستانه اي باهم داشته باشيم
What I wouldn't give to be 20 years younger,
اينم بدونين هيوقتم آرزو نداشتم که يه بيست سالي جوونتر باشم
and a woman.
يا اينکه يه زن باشم
You know, I've flown over 194 missions, and I was shot down on every one.
خوب ميدونين که من در بيشتر از 194 مأموريت شرکت داشتم و آدماي زياديم کشتم
Come to think of it, I've never landed a plane in my life. Now,
اينم ميدونين که تا حالا تو عمرم يه هوايما هم به زمين ننشوندم..الان
you men'll be piloting the backbone of our proud American arsenal:
شما خلباناي اين سرزمين هستين و همه به شما افتخار ميکنن
The Oscar EW 5894 Phallus tactical fighter bomber.
هوايماي "اسکار5894"،يه جننده بمب افکن تاکتيکي بحساب مياد
Its lightweight sweptwing design makes it extremely manoeuvrable and agile.
وزن کمي داره و طراحيش باعث ميشه که هم سريع و هم قدرت مانور بالايي داشته باشه
Beneath its 21st-century skin is a highly advanced avionics and weapons package.
يه جننده يشرفته در قرن بيست و يکم که ميتونين با ضبط و خشش هايده وش بدين
Designed for speed and combat acrobatics,
اين طراحي يعني سرعت و قدرت در مبارزه
it features the latest Mrs Halver series 3800 radar-jamming Framus.
از ويژيهاي ديه اين جننده قابليت استفاده از 3800 رادار مختلفه
- Admiral. - Nurse.
آدميرال رستار
Sleepy Weasel's success depends on our manoeuvring below enemy radar.
موفقيت در عمليات "راسوي خفته" بستي به قدرت مانور ما زير رادار دشمن داره
I wanna see a major display of low-level flying. Topper, Kent, you're up first.
همه به مانيتور ناه کنين،فيلم سور نبينين ها تار" و "کنت" اولين رواز با شماست"
- Show me what you can do. - Copy that, Purple Fluffer Nutter.
دوست دارم که خودتونو به من نشون بدين بايد به ياد يه قلب بنفش باشين
Roger that, Milli Vanilli Chilly Willy.
و بعدشم "راجر" و "ويلي" آماده باشين
Bring 'em down, boys. I want your bellies to
بايد برين ايينتر به ها..
scrape the sagebrush. Let's see who's best.
تا جايي که سر قله تراشيده بشه،ببينم کي بهتر انجامش ميده
I'm heading for the canyon floor.
الان داخل يه دره باريک و عميقم
- For your information, I'm at 150 feet. - I'm at 3rd and Main.
و بايد بم که الان ارتفاع نزديک 150 است من ميميرم   برا 3 بعدي
Very pretty, but enough hot-dogging, Harley.
خيلي خوبه،ولي کاري نکن تا "مردم بشاشن به خودشون"تار
Just checkin' the traffic.
نزديک بود داخل ترافيک ير کنم
- How'd I do, big fella? - Don't get me started, Harley.
به نظرت جوري بود؟ "ميخواي يه بار ديه انجامش بدم "تار
Cut the chatter. Topper, that was vintage Buzz Harley.
ساکت شدي "تار"..ه خبر بود ايين
You and your dad are two of a kind.
تو و درت عين هم مي مونين
Your ego's writin' cheques your body can't cash.
موندم که را وقتي ک ميکشي يادت ميره حسابتو ر کني
Topper! Get back in formation!
يکار ميکني "تار"؟ برميرديم بحالت اول
Topper, you weren't clear to detach.
از وسط نصفشون کردي که
- What was that all about? - I, uh... thought I saw Elvis.
باز داشتي به ي فکر ميکردي؟ يه لحظه "الويس" اومد جلو نظرم
Let it go, Topper. The King is gone. Let's head for home.
خيله خب،حالا از هم جدا ميشيم برميرديم به اياه
Not again!
باز شروع شد
I need a landing clearance for runway 30... 30 something.
من دارم فرود ميام برج مراقبت به باند 30..30 نزديک ميشم
30-thirty-something's been cancelled. Go to runway 2-niner.
فرود روي باند 30..30 لغو شده برو به باند 2..9
Wash Out, what the hell are you doin'? Pull it up.
باند خيسه..کدوم جهنمي داري ميري يکار داري ميکني؟
Wash Out, where the hell are you? What is your location? You're off of radar.
س کدوم وري رفتي؟موقعيتتو اعلام کن رادارت را خاموشه
Repeat: What is your location?
تکرار ميکنم..اعلام موقعيت کن
It's not unusual to be loved by anyone
خونه خاله نيست که هر جا عشقت کشيد بري
- Goin' up? - Yes.
ميري بالا؟ آره
Can I press your button?
ميتوني دکمه طبقه رو فشار بدي؟
No, you've been slavin' over hot psychotics all day. Let me get that.
نه،آخه من يه آدم روانريش بي عقلم ولي الان فشار ميدم
- Interesting perfume. - It's Vicks. I have a cold.
به به ه عطري زدي اين بوي ويکسه..سرماخوردم
Ah.
آه.
Lieutenant, you're staring.
به ي زُل زدي ستوان
No, not really. I'm lost in your eyes.
نه،نه زل نزدم..شمام هرز شدن
That is the whitest white part of the eye I've ever seen. Do you floss?
آدم به شم سفيدي شما نديده بودم تا حالا..هميشه اين شکلين؟
You're very confident, aren't you?
شما اعتماد به نفس بالايي دارين درسته؟
When you have 10,000 pounds of thrust at your command, you have to be.
وقتي که به شمام 10000 وند فشار وارد بکنن همينجوري ميشين ديه
Lieutenant, please. I'm talking to you as a psychiatrist.
خواهش ميکنم ستوان..من الان دارم بعنوان يه روانشناس باهاتون حرف ميزنم
I'm recommending that you be grounded.
فقط ميخوام بهترين مسيرو بهتون نشون بدم
- You've got to be joking. - If I were joking, I'd have said...
داري شوخي ميکني شوخي مال زير لحافه نه اينجا
"What do you do with an elephant with three balls?"
تا حالا ديدي يه فيل با سه تا تو يکار ميکنه؟
"You walk him and pitch to the rhino."
عين شما راه ميره و مثه کردن شوت ميزنه
- You are serious. - It's the best thing for you, and the mission.
راست ميي بهترين راه اينه که خودتونو يدا کنين
The best would be if you'd stop tryin' to run my life.
بهترين راهه ،درصورتيکه شما هم دست از سر کل من بردارين
I'm a pilot, and nobody's gonna keep me out of the sky.
من يه خلبانم و هيکسم حق نداره آسمونو ازم بيره
Ladies and gentlemen! Twelve rounds of boxing
خانمها و آقايان دوازده راند نفس ير
for the WBA WBC WPA RSVP
براي WBA WBC WPA RSVP
Heavyweight Championship of the World!
مسابقات قهرماني سنين وزن جهان
Introducing celebrities at ringside,
به همراه بزرترين مشاهير اين عرصه,
please welcome His Holiness, the very popular pontiff,
لطفاً تشويقشون کنين همراه با ا مهربان يعني
Pope John Paul II!
"ا ژان ل دوم"
Second!
دوم
Lieutenant Commander Block. We meet at last.
"جناب فرمانده  "بلاک خيلي وقته که نديدمت
- Isn't this place a little public? - No, a crowd offers remarkable anonymity.
فکر نميکني اينجا يه کم شلوغ باشه؟ نه اتفاقاً از جمعيت بعنوان وشش استفاده ميکنيم
How are we doing at Dudley?
حالا در "دادلي" يکار بايد بکنيم؟
Oh, we're right on schedule.
اوه،ما يه برنامه حساب شده رديف کرديم
Can't quite get a reading on Admiral Benson,
با آدميرال "بنسون" نميشه به راحتي کنار اومد
but Topper Harley's playing into our hands.
ولي "تار" عين موم تو مشت خودمونه
Here's his evaluation. A clear-cut case of Paternal Conflict Syndrome.
يه کم خوددريري يدا کرده واضح بم،به سندرم تضاد در دار شده
Ah, yes. PCS.
"آه درسته..همون "ي سي اس
I saw an Afterschool Special on that. They're years away from a vaccine.
در يه مدرسه اسثنايي باهاش آشنا شدم ولي هنوز واکسني واسش کشف نشده
Every time I mention Buzz's name, Topper goes off.
استفاده ميکنم فوري واکنش نشون ميده"BUZZ"هر بار که از کلمه
There's no way the unit will function, and I'll abort the mission.
هي اره اي ندارم جز اينکه اين مأموريتو لغوش کنم
The Navy's planes will seem inferior and the
اين هوايماها واقعن فرسوده شدن ديه از
president will beg for my superfighter.
رئيس جمهور درخواست جننده جديد ميکنم
And, best of all, nobody gets hurt.
اينجوري واسه هيکسم اتفاقي نميفته ديه
Well done, Lieutenant Commander.
به نظرم بهترين کار ممکن همينه
America can't afford to fall behind, Mr Wilson. We need your plane.
آمريکا هم نبايد همراه با آقاي "ويلسون" سقوط کنه..بايد کل هوايماها به روز بشن
This should be a good match. Both men work for Don King.
بايد رقابت جالبي باشه آخه هردوشون واسه "دان کين" کار ميکنن
Well, fans, that's it.
عجب فني زد
Good night. I'm outta here!
خب ديه مسابقه تموم شد و به همتون شب بخير ميم
The Strafing Run proudly presents Lawrence Lipps!
The Strafing Run proudly presents Lawrence Lipps!
And now...
And now...
What the world needs
What the world needs
Thank you!
Thank you!
Is love
Is love
Thank you so much!
Thank you so much!
That's the only thing that there's just too darn little of
That's the only thing that there's just too darn little of
Ramada?
"رامادا"
- Kent! - Ramada!
"کنت"
Qu'est-ce que je suis contente de te revoir.
نميدوني سر قدر از ديدنت خوشحال شدم
Argh! My eyes!
آي شمام
Darling, I thought you were still in Brussel.
عزيزم،فکر ميکردم که هنوز "بروکسل" زندي ميکني
Oh, Kent. We were only hurting each other.
اوه "کنت"..ما خيلي رفتار بدي نسبت بهم داشتيم
I thought that's the way you wanted it.
ولي فکر ميکنم که خودت يه نين يزيو انتخاب کردي
Something's changed. It's not another woman, is it? I couldn't compete with that.
خب شرايط عوض شده بود..اي يه زن ديه هم به ميون اومده بود،ولي باهاش کنار نميومدم
No, of course you couldn't.
نه،ميدونم که هي تقصيري نداري تو
Well, what matters is that you're here. We've a lot of catching up to do.
ولش کن،مهم اينه که الان اينجايي و بايد باهم کلي خوش بذرونيم
Wonderful. Just let me take care of something.
عاليه..ولي قبلش اجازه بده يه کاري دارم انجام بدم برميردم
- Don't be long, mon amour. - Absolument.
طولاني نشه که خيلي تو کفم نه عزيزم الان ميام
Some day he'll come along
Some day he'll come along
The man I love
The man I love
And he'll be big and strong
And he'll be big and strong
And when he comes my way
And when he comes my way
I'll do my best
I'll do my best
To make... him... stay
To make... him... stay
He'll look at me and smile
He'll look at me and smile
I'll understand
I'll understand
And in a little while
And in a little while
He'll take my hand
He'll take my hand
And though it seems absurd
And though it seems absurd
I know we both... won't say... a... word
I know we both... won't say... a... word
Wow!
Wow!
Anybody here from out of town?
کسي هست که از جاي ديه اي به اين شهر اومده باشه؟
Welcome. Nice to see you.
خوش اومدين ممنون که اومدين
Maybe I shall meet him someday
Maybe I shall meet him someday
Maybe Monday
Maybe Monday
Maybe not
Maybe not
Still I'm sure to meet him one day
Still I'm sure to meet him one day
Maybe Tuesday
Maybe Tuesday
Will be my good-news day
Will be my good-news day
We'll build a little home
We'll build a little home
Just meant for two
Just meant for two
From which I'll never roam
From which I'll never roam
Who would? Would you?
Who would? Would you?
And so all else above
And so all else above
I'm dreaming of
I'm dreaming of
The man... I... love
The man... I... love
One day he'll come along
One day he'll come along
He'll be big and strong
He'll be big and strong
And when he comes my way
And when he comes my way
I'll do my best to make him stay
I'll do my best to make him stay
And so all else above
And so all else above
I'm dreamin' of
I'm dreamin' of
The man I love
The man I love
- Ramada... - Oh, no.
"عالي بود "رامادا اوه, نه .
Well, if it isn't God's gift to the cockpit.
جالبه،نکنه فکر کردي اينم کابين خلبانه که بشيني روش
- Kent, your nostrils are flaring. - That flying stunt today was pure madness.
داره از دماغت بخار بلند ميشه به اندازه کافي با خلبانيت نمک ريختي خيارشور
If a lady wasn't present, I'd tear you apart like a Christmas goose.
اه با يه خانوم محترم روبرو شدي زود نبايد واسش راست کني جناب روانريش
Yeah? Keep it up, you'll be carrying your face home in a doggy bag.
باشه،اَرزونيه خودت..ولي يادت نره که خودتم يه اورون بيشتر نبودي خرسوار
What is this macho thing?
اين ه رفتاريِ که شما دارين؟
- He started it. - Did not.
اين ميمون شروع کرد زر نزن بابا
- Did too.
تو زر نزن خودت زر نزن
- You're behaving like children. - He's a jerk.
عين دو تا به افتادن به جون هم بايد از خجالتش درميومدم
- Am not. - Are too.
تقصير من نيست را هست
- Are too too too...
ميم نيست هست..هست
- Not not not... ...too too too...
نيست..نيست..نيست هست..هست..هست
Are too times ten.
بيشتر از ده بار
- That's it. - Stop it.
خيله خب بس کنين ديه
- Rumble! - Don't push me.
"رامبل" دستتو بکش
Stop it! Can't you act like civilised human beings?
بسه ديه نميشه مثل دو تا آدم باهم رفتار کنين؟
- Hey, I'm sorry. - I love you, pal.
هي،واقعاً متأسفم خيلي دوست دارم
Listen. Kent and I have to talk, so please...
وش کن،من بايد با "کنت" حرف بزنم ..س لطفاً
Be my guest.
س مهمون من باشين ديه
Let's celebrate, honey.
ي دوست داري عسلم
Hey, everybody. Drinks are on me.
هي،اين ند نفرم مهمون منن
- Free beer! - I want a gin sling!
آبجو منم جين ميخورم
You haven't forgotten my offer, have you?
يشنهاد من که هنوز يادته ديه..آره؟
Little house in the country, white picket fence, StairMaster.
يه خونه نقلي کوولو با نرده هاي سفيد و له هاي رو به آسمون
Kent, you're everything a woman could possibly want.
مطمئنم "کنت" که واسه يه زن هيوقت يزي کم نميذاري
But I'm just not ready for marriage. Not yet.
ولي من هنوز واسه ازدواج آمادي ندارم هنوز نه
Well, I have to get back to the base. Tomorrow's an important flight.
خيله خب،من ديه بايد برردم اياه فردا يه رواز مهم دارم
You know how puffy my eyes get when I don't get enough rest.
بايد برم استراحت کنم که ديه شمامو نميتونم باز نه دارم
Good night.
شب بخير
May I?
اجازه هست؟
- Shouldn't you be getting back to the base? - I suppose,
مه نبايد برردي به اياه؟ فکر ميکنم
if I played life by the rules, but you know I don't.
درسته زندي منو به بازي رفته ولي بايد بدوني که به راحتي دُم به تله نميدم
All right. You can walk me to my apartment.
خيله خب،س اه وقت داري منو تا آارتمانم همراهي کن
I shouldn't have gotten mad in the elevator today.
قبول دارم که امروز داخل آسانسور رفتار احمقانه اي داشتم
But when I want something that bad, I get all fired up.
ولي اينم بم که اين رفتار مزخرفم از وقتي که اخراج شدم شروع شده
Maybe that's why I worry so. Maybe more than I should.
شايد دليل نراني منم همين باشه واسه همينم فتم که تحت درمان باشي
Something terrible could happen. You must...
ممکنه بدتر از اينم بشه ..شايد تو بايد
- But I... - Don't worry.
..آخه من نران نباش
Everything will be fine. I promise.
قول ميدم که به زودي همه ي درست ميشه
Boy, I hope so.
منم اميدوارم
Well, this is it.
خيله خب..ديه رسيديم
- It's a nice place. - It's OK.
محله خوبيه خيلي راضيم
The only problem is I have a nosy landlady.
تنها مشکلم يه زن کارر فضوله که بايد تحملش کنم
Well, I guess this is good night.
خب،فکر ميکنم شب نسبتاً خوبي بود
I don't wanna go back.
دوست ندارم دوباره به ذشته برردم
You don't have to.
لازم نيست که بهش فکر کني
I don't want to be alone.
منم دوست ندارم که تنها باشم
And, by the way, I can go all night like a lumberjack.
و تموم شب عين يه وب خشک به در و ديوار خيره بشم
What about your landlady?
با اون زن فضول يکار کنيم؟
You can do her, too.
هر که طاووس خواهد جور هندوستان کشد
So, I take it you've been with a man before.
فکر ميکردم که قبلاً با يه مرد ديه رابطه داشتي
I'm a virgin.
من باکره ام
I'm just not very good at it.
واسه همينم کسي نميتونه توش بکنه
Ooh!
اوه!
Ah!
اه!
Yes. Oh, yes...
آره..همينه
Ah! Topper...
"تار"
Oh...
اوه...
Wash Out!
کجا ميري
Get into your flight suit. We're ready to go up.
واسه ي لباس نوشيدي بايد آماده رواز بشيم
I got kicked out. My flight status has been withdrawn.
اخراج شدم..از شيوه خلباني من راضي نيستن
I'm through, Dead Meat.
ديه خودمم باورم شده که شاسکولم
- What happened? - It's my eyes. I've got walleye vision.
آخه واسه ي؟ بخاطر شماي کُلاجم..همه يرو هل تا مي بينم
- Can't something be done? - A delicate corneal inversion procedure.
حالا ميشه درمانش کرد يا نه؟ با يه روشي بنام واروني قرنيه
A multioptipupiloptomy.
ميشه بهترش کرد
But, to keep from damaging the eye sockets,
ولي مين بخاطر اينکه کاسه شمم صدمه نبينه
they've gotta go in through the rectum.
مجبورن يه يزي  داخل سوراخ کونم فرو کنن
Ain't no man gonna take that route with me.
مطمئناً هي مردي يه همين يزي دوست نداره ديه
Is Topper around? I'd like to say goodbye.
تو "تار" رو نديدي؟ ميخوام ازش خداحافظي کنم
He didn't come back last night. He's AWOL.
از ديشب هنوز برنشته..
As soon as Block finds out, he's history.
اين روزا سرش به کونش نالتي ميزنه..خيلي يج ميزنه
But flying's his life. He's the best pilot in the world.
ولي به زودي رواز ميکنه،يکي از بهترين خلباناي دنياست
We need him as much as he needs us.
ما هم خيلي بهش نياز داريم
I can't find my lucky gum. Do you have...
نميدونم آدامس شانسمو يکار کردم ..تو نديدي
Wash Out?
کجا رفتي؟
Oh, my God. I missed my flight.
آه،خدا..روازم از دست رفت که
You're amazing.
عاشقتم عزيزم
Dead Meat!
"وشت مُرده"
Mary!
"هي "ماري
- Come to watch me fly? - No. There was a meltdown at the plant.
اومدي رواز منو تماشا کني؟ نه يه اتفاق بدي افتاده که بايد ميومدم
- They gave me afternoon off. - Terrific!
کارخونه رو تعطيل کردن ديه عاليه که
Oh! Good news. We just closed escrow on our little dream house.
خيلي خبر خوبيه..حالا راحت ميتونيم بريم عشق و حال و ددر دودور
- Wonderful! When do we move in? - Tuesday.
اين عاليه که..حالا کي حرکت کنيم؟ سه شنبه
The kids are stripping the asbestos off the pipes now.
الانم به ها دارن لوله هاي قديمي آزبست رو جمع و جور ميکنن
That's great! Things couldn't be better for us.
خيلي خوبه..اينجوري کار ما هم راحتتر ميشه
I'm so blessed.
من آدم خوشبختيم
Oh! Your life insurance forms came for you to sign.
آه،راستي يه فرم بيمه عمر آوردم تا رش کني
Oh, my mirror!
اوه..آينه م شکست
Huh!
ها!
- I'll get another pen. - No need. I'll sign it when I get back.
بذار يه خودکار بهت بدم لازم نيست،وقتي برشتم امضاش ميکنم
Well, you know best.
باشه،ميدونستي که قدر خوبي
Honey, you know that global-warming problem? I know how we can reverse it.
عزيزم،تو ميدوني که دليل رمايش جهان يه؟ من ميدونم جوري بايد جلوشو بيريم
- Tell me. - No, not now, lovey-bumpers.
خب جوري؟ نه..نه الان زوده که بم
There'll be plenty of time for that later.
اما همنان روشهاي بيشتري واسه مهارش کشف ميشه
And my investigation into JFK's assassination?
و تحقيقات من بر اساس جي..اف..کي بنا شده
You found the evidence you wanted?
حالا اين تحقيقات نتيجه اي واست داشته يا نه؟
Yes. It's right here in my pocket. It's big, honey.
آره..همش همينجا داخل جيبمه،اينقدر مهمه عزيزم
It goes all the way to the White House.
که بخاطرش منو ميبرن کاخ سفيد
- Do you want me to hold it for you? - Nah. It'll be safe right here.
ميخواي من واست نهشون دارم؟ خب..فکر کنم همينجا جاش امن باشه
I'm in a jet. What could go wrong?
به اين مين جت دوست داري سوار بشي؟
Oh, Dead Meat. We just couldn't be any more perfectly happy.
اوه،عزيزم..اه قراره بري اون دنيا ميشينم کنارت و بعدشم باهم بريم اون دنيا
Where the hell is Topper?
س اين "تار" احمق کدوم وريه؟
Thanks for joinin' the party!
ممنونم از اينکه به اين تيم ملحق شدي
Hey, Topper! You seen any of my lucky gum?
هي "تار"،تو اين آدامس شانس منو نديدي؟
No.
نه
Freedom Squadron, start your engines.
خلبانان توجه کنن موتورها روشن
God, that's loud. My ear canals are very sensitive. Stainless steel.
واي خدا،اين ي بود،من که شاشيدم بخودم آخه من وشام عين کانال يکسره شدن
Took a bullet in Corregidor. Passed straight through. Look at this.
يادمه يه بار يه لوله از اين طرف رفت داخل و از اون طرف دراومد..ببينين کف کنين
Huh?
ها?
We have these to hold down the sound, sir.
آخه قربان ما با اين يزا وشامونو ميبنديم
Oh, good. Thanks.
اوه،قدر خوب..ممنون
Let's hope they do the trick. Give me the mike, boy.
الان ميندازم بالا بده منم يه صحبتي با به ها بکنم
For the love of God, man, be careful!
مه سرت با کونت بازي ميکنه الاغ
Ever since Normandy, this is CorningWare.
حالا هي اين غده مارو جابجا کنين
Those of you who excel during these aerial combat exercises
نميخوام خرتون بکنم ولي بايد بم که شما از بهترين خلبانان جهان هستين
will go on to make up the greatest fighting unit ever assembled.
شما باعملکردتون يکي از بزرترين و بهترين واحدها رو خلق کردين
- Topper, keep that nose up! - He's never done that before.
هي "تار"،داري ه غلطي ميکني همين کاري تا حالا نکرده بود
Red team leader, break off. Prepare to engage.
فرمانده تيم قرمز صحبت مينکه همه آماده..شروع ميکنيم
Roger that.
آماده
- Blue leader, prepare for action. - Roger that.
فرمانده تيم آبي..همه آماده باشن
I'm minus six. Movin' in.
موقعيت روي منفي شش حالا ميرم
I've got tone! Got him!
الان مي يرمش حالا سبيدم بهش
Dead Meat, confirm kill.
وشت مرده"..تآييدش کن"
- Mrs Thompson? - Yes.
خانوم "تامسون"؟ بله
- I'm Topper Harley. - Oh! Dead Meat's talked about you!
من ستوان "تار" هستم وشت مرده" قبلاً دربارتون بهم فته بود"
Oh, he thinks the world of you!
اوه،اون ميه که شما تو يه دنياي ديه سير ميکنين
But... shouldn't you be up there flying with the squad?
مه شما الان نبايد اون بالا باشين؟ همراه با بقيه رواز کنين
I've got a lock. I'm closing in.
حالا روش قفل کردن بسته شد
- Uh-oh! - He's spotted me! He's a slippery devil.
اون را خال خاليه يه دشمن متحرک
Topper! Watch your right side! Damn!
تار"..برو به سمت راست..در الاغ يکار ميکني"
I'm bailin' out!
الان ميزنم بيرون
Wash Out? What are you doin' here?
هي "واش"..تو اين بالا يکار ميکين؟
There's no time to go into it.
تا حالا يه همنين جايي نيومده بودم سر
Uh-oh!
او-اوه!
Do me a favour, don't land.
نبايد فرود بياي اينجوري بهتره
- Get outta here! We're gonna crash! - I can't! I'm stuck!
برو بيرون الاغ،داريم سقوط ميکنيم نميتونم،آخه ير کردم
Then I must help you, my friend! Think well of me!
الان يه کاري ميکنم تا شاي ت راست بشه تا همين ُهي نخوري ديه
Thank youuuuu...
ممنونم
- Don't. Don't look. - Oh, no!
نه..نه..ناه نکن اوه،نه
Whoa!
اي واي!
Oh, man!
اوه , مرد!
Wendy, I can fly!
وندي"،من دارم رواز ميکنم"
- Hey, Topper. - Easy, buddy.
"هي "تار زنده اي؟
- The darnedest thing just happened. - Hang on, buddy.
من الان کجام، تو بهشتم قدر فرشته
Topper?
ستوان؟
Swing him around this way.
فقط يه کم به درو ديوار خورد
Let's go. One, two...
بده بره بالا ..يک دو
Let's move it. Come on!
بجُنب حرکت کن.عجله کن
- Come on! - Enough!
زود باش..بزن تا بره تو
Hello!
سلام به همي
We'll have you in the hospital in no time.
آروم باش سر داريم ميرسيم بيمارستان
Good morning! Excuse me!
صبح بخير معذرت ميخوام
Wait, guys! Wait!
وايسين به ها صبر کنين
Let's go, let's go.
زود باشين..بيرش
Easy. Easy, easy, easy.
يواش..مواظب باش..آروم
- Let's move. - What a ride!
بذار بازش کنم رخ داره
- Wash Out. You made it. - Why, thank you, André.
هي سر خوب کاري کردي که اومدي خواهش ميکنم..وظيفه ست
I'll have the veal piccata.
الان مثل يه وشت وساله شدم
- Oh. Get the cardio read-out. - Where is it?
اوه،يادمون رفت.. برو اون دستاهو بردار بيار کجاست؟
- Um... It's, uh... - Hey, fellas...
همونجاست در اينطرفي
- Inside there on the left. - I can't find it!
همين جلوست من که نمي بينم
- Doctor! - What happened?
دکتر ي شده؟
Plane crash.
هوايماش سقوط کرده
- We gotta work fast. I got a lunch. - You're missing the big picture, Doc.
زود باشين که بايد برم واسه ناهار اين داره ميميره دکتر..بري ناهار..؟
Nurse, check his penis isn't longer than mine.
رستار،ک کن ببين کيرش از مال من بزرتر نيست
- No, Doctor. - Good. Now this is gonna hurt.
نه دکتر خوبه..اصل مطلب مشکل نداره
Ow!
آخ!
Nurse, give me 15cc of morphine, quickly!
رستار،15 سي سي مُرفين..عجله کن
- Can you save him? - Can't be sure. I'm not a good doctor.
ميشه نجاتش داد؟ نميدونم..ون من دکتر واردي نيستم زياد
Thank you, Nurse. Wait here.
ممنون رستار شما همينجا بمونين
- You gonna be all right, buddy? - I'm in a hospital! What could go wrong?
با تموم سرعت رو به جلو..آماده اين؟ اينجا بيمارستانه..درست برين ديه
Mrs Thompson, I know you must hate me but... there's something I want you to have.
خانوم "تامسون"،من واقعاً نميدونم ي بايد بم ولي يه يزي هست که بايد بهتون بدم
I've been puttin' a little away for the past ten years.
حدود ده سال يش يه بليط بخت آزمايي خريده بودم که بالاخره بردم
It's not much. 2500. I wish I could do more.
ناقابله..2500 تا کاش بيشتر برده بودم
Why, Topper.
"ممنونم "تار
That's so sweet.
نميدونم ي بايد بم
Why, with the three million I won on this lucky Lotto ticket,
را،را نبايد بليطش سه ميليون ببره را من نبايد ببرم
I can take this 2500 and just blow it all on hats.
با اين ول يه فکم نميدن ولي بازم ممنون
Right, and halt!
به راست راست ايست
Pete "Dead Meat" Thompson... is dead.
الان "يت تامسون" همون "وشت مرده" خودمون به يه جاي دور سفر کرده
So is Mo Green,
بايد جاشو سبز نهداريم
Tataglia, Barzini,
اينم بايد بم که
the heads of all the five families.
اون در نج تا به قد و نيم قد بود
It is at moments like these, my dear friends that we must ask ourselves,
و در نين لحظاتي دوستان عزيزم بايد از خودمون برسيم که
"How can this not be part of some larger plan?"
واقعاً طوري ميتونيم يکي ديه رو جايزين اين شخص بزر بکنيم؟
Do good men like Dead Meat Thompson just blink out one day like a bad bulb?
آيا خوباني ون "وشت مرده" در يه شم بهم زدن زاده ميشن يا مثه يه شمک لام خاموش؟
One minute you're in bed with a knockout gal, or guy,
اه واسه يه لحظه تصور کنين که ديه در رختخواب کسي کنارتون نيست
and the next, you're a compost heap.
و بعد تبديل به يه کموست..به يه توده آشغال شده باشين
Doesn't that bother you? Because it scares the living piss outta me!
خدا وکيلي ناراحت نميشين؟ س ون آدمو ميترسونه بايد بشاشيم به همين فکري
I never thought this could happen.
هرز فکر نميکردم که نين اتفاقي بيفته
Don't we have what we need now, Mr Wilson?
به نظرتون الان يکار ميشه کرد آقاي "ويلسون"؟
This should be enough to prove that our planes need replacing.
بايد تا جايي که ميتونيم و امکان داره هوايماهاي جديد رو جايزين کنيم
No. They have to fail in combat for the world
نه،با اينکار همه جاي دنيا مي يه که ما شکست خورده ايم
to take notice. This is a minor incident.
اونم واسه يه حادثه جزئي
Minor? I just lost one of my best men!
جزئي..؟من الان يکي از بهترين افرادمو از دست دادم
Are you backing out on us, Block?
يعني ما مهم نيستيم "بلاک"..؟
I'm doing this for my country,
واسه من فقط کشورم مهمه
not for you.
نه شما
We'll need the backup plan.
بايد به حامي جديدي فکر بکنيم
Ready... Fire!
آماده..آتش
Jumpin' Jesus, they're back!
يا عيسي مسيح ه زود حمله کردن
Take cover! Hit the deck!
بخوابين رو زمين منو وشش بدين
Battle stations! Battle stations!
همه نيروها آماده ناه بيرين
Have they no respect for the dead?
جون يه مُرده هم واسشون اهميت نداره.واقعاً که
God, I love a good funeral.
خدايا،من عاشق يه نين تشييع جنازه ايم.
Topper, where are you going?
کجا داري ميري "تار"؟
I'm handin' in my resignation.
دارم ميرم استعفا بدم..
You were right. You said I was dangerous, and I am.
حق با تو بود من خيلي آدم خطرناکيم
Topper, wait.
"صبر کن "تار
Please, let's talk. Huh?
اه ممکنه قبلش حرف بزنيم
They're right. I'm no better than my father.
حق با تو بود هيوقت به اي درم نميرسم
It seems, no matter what I do, I end up hurting someone.
به نظرم اه همينجوري ادامه بدم به افراد بيشتري آسيب ميرسونم
Ow!
واي!
You've got to stop comparing yourself with your father.
هيوقت نبايد خودتو با درت مقايسه کني
You're two different people.
شما دوتا آدم متفاوت و مختلفي هستين
- We both killed a man. - That's just a coincidence.
الان دونفر کشته شدن که فقط يه حادثه بوده
He loved jets. So do I.
عاشق جت بود همنين عاشق من
He was a loner, just like me.
آدم خيلي تنهايي بود درست شبيه من
For God's sakes, I've even got my father's eyes.
خدا ميدونه که منو از شماش نزديکتر به خودش ميدونست
- Topper, please! - Ah, they're just for luck.
"خواهش ميکنم "تار هميشه يه شانس ديه واسه موفقيت وجود داره
You've got to make your own luck.
را يه شانس ديه به خودت نميدي
Get back in the sky and prove yourself.
بررد به آسمون و دوباره خودتو به همه ثابت کن
Besides, there's something else.
علاوه بر اين يزاي ديه ايم وجود داره.
After our first meeting in my office, I sent my evaluation to Commander Block.
بعد از اولين جلسه صحبتمون،من ارزيابي خودمو واسه فرمانده "بلاک" فرستادم
I recommended you be grounded. I was afraid someone might get hurt.
من معتقدم که يه جاي کار داره مي لنه يه کسي داره با نين حوادثي همرو ميترسونه
What are you saying?
ي ميخواي بي؟
I think someone wants Sleepy Weasel to fail.
به نظرم يکي داره تلاش ميکنه تا عمليات "راسوي خفته" شکست بخوره
- That's heavy. - Totally.
ضربه سنينيه نهايتاً
That's the other reason why you need to fly.
نين دليلي باعث ميشه که تو برردي و ادامه بدي
This could be your only opportunity to save the mission
اين مآموريت بهترين فرصت واسه اينه که خودتو نشون بدي
and solve your personal problems, all in one fell swoop.
و بتوني همه مشکلات شخصي خودتو با همين يه رواز حل کني
Now read it back to me, Francine.
"واسم بخونش "فرانسيس
"And if you ever put your goddamn hands on my wife again..."
و اه فقط يه بار ديه ببينم که دست کثيفت ..به همسرم بخوره
- You wanted to see me, sir? - Oh, Blank. Come in.
با من کار داشتين قربان؟ آه،"بلاک"..بيا تو
I've been expecting someone.
منتظر يکي ديه بودم
- That'll be all, Francine. - Yes, sir.
تموم شد "فرانسيس"؟ بله قربان
- Pudding? - No, thank you, sir.
ميخوري؟ نه ممنونم قربان
I'll put this to you straight. Thompson's death shocked us all.
بذار يه يزيو سرراست بهت بم مر "تامسون" همه مارو شوکه کرد
And that hot shot Harley is responsible.
و الان هري که داريم ميکشيم از دست اين نخود آش يعني "تار"
I want that smirking little wise-ass outta here.
،ميخوام بندازيش بيرون
Morale on this base is shot to hell. Just look out there.
تا وقتيکه اين طالع نحس اينجا باشه همين آش و همين کاسه ست
Quiet. Now, hardly a man moving.
اينم شد اياه رنده ر نميزنه توش
Roy? Roy!
"هي "روي".."روي
Huh? I even went to school with that man. It's just not the same.
ميبيني؟انار نه انار که منم آدمم تازه فقط همين نيست که
Been ignoring me all day. Remind me to send him a note.
در تمام طول روز غيبش ميزنه تأکيد ميکنم که مواظبش باشي
Sir, may I say something?
قربان،ميشه يه يزي بم؟
I know Harley acted irresponsibly.
ميدونم که کار "تار"،کار درستي نبوده.
But his kind lives on the edge. Always willing to take a chance.
ولي الان روي لبه رتاه قرار داره و دوست داره که يه شانس ديه بهش بديم
Now, we need Topper for this mission for just that reason.
فقط به همين دليل در اين مأموريت بهش نياز داريم
I like your thinking, Colonel.
از اين حرفت خوشم اومد سرهن
Besides, Thompson wasn't that good a pilot.
علاوه بر اين "تامسون"خلبان خوبيم نبود
He only had a small family. The kids are a
يه عنصر فرعي بيشتر نبود..
pain in the ass. The wife's on the sauce.
درسته آننان آش دهنسوزيم نبود
Poor bastard's better off dead.
يه حرومزاده ضعيف بهتر از يه مرده بي خاصيته ديه
What size shoes do you wear?
سايز کفشت نده؟
- A nine, sir. - Good.
نُه قربان خوبه
It's settled. We'll send Harley to the front.
س خودت به فکر باش ببينم با اين "تار" يکار ميکني ديه
By the way. Thank you for having us over to dinner the other night.
بابت اين همه زحمتي که ميکشي ممنونم..بايد يه شب شام باهم باشيم
Cheryl and I loved the stroganoff.
من و "شريل" خيلي "بيف استراانف" دوست داريم
- Sir, we didn't have dinner the other night. - Really?
قربان،ولي ما اصلاً شام نميخوريم واقعاً؟
Well, where the hell was I? And who's this Cheryl?
خب،اين واسه من يعني جهنم س با "شريل" يکار کنم؟
Ah, doesn't matter.
آه مهم نيست
Run along, Sid.
آدم اينجوري سالمتر مي مونه ديه
Cheryl?
"شريل"
Kent?
"کنت"
I came to get my chafing dish. Our orders just came.
اومدم ظرف غذامو بردارم.
We're shipping out in one hour.
تا يه ساعت ديه بايد حرکت کنيم
Are you comin' along this time?
ميخواي بدمش به تو؟
- The chafing dish is not yours. - It is.
اين ظرف غذا که مال تو نيست هست
- It isn't. - OK, I don't want it.
نه نيست باشه من اونو نميخوام
- I'll take it. - You stay out of it.
بيا بيرش فتم که نميخوامش
This is not the time or place.
الان وقت خوبي نيست
I've got a big score to settle with you, my friend.
به وقتش حسابمو با تو تصفيه ميکنم شاسکول
Excuse me.
ببخشيد
I've hurt him.
کار بدي کردم
Topper...
"تار"
Topper, you better go. I have to think.
تار"،به نظرم بهتره که بري ديه"
Well, I don't.
راستش،ديه نميتونم
- I've fallen for you like a blind roofer. - I'm sorry?
من مثه يه شتر صاف افتادم وسط زنديت ببخشيد..؟
My heart is fallin' down around my ankles like a wet pair of pants.
الان قلبم افتاده ايين کنار مُ ام عين اه خيس شلوارم حسش ميکنم
My whole life, all I've wanted to do is fly.
در کل زنديم،هميشه عاشق رواز کردن بودم
Bomb stuff. Shoot people down.
عاشق بمب و خماره عاشق شليک به مردم
But we've been through so much together. Ramada, I need you.
ولي ما نقاط مشترکي زيادي داريم باهم "من بهت نياز دارم "رامادا
I want you.
من فقط تورو ميخوام
Only you
Only you
Can make this world seem bright
Can make this world seem bright
Can make the darkness bright
Can make the darkness bright
Wow!
Wow!
Only you, and you alone
Only you, and you alone
Can thrill me like you do
Can thrill me like you do
And fill my heart with love for only you
And fill my heart with love for only you
Wah, wah, wah, wah
Wah, wah, wah, wah
Ramada!
"رامادا"
Topper!
"تار"
I love you!
من عاشقتم
I love you.
منم عاشقتم
You are my destiny
You are my destiny
It's not that easy, Ramada.
"کار ساده اي نيست واسم "رامادا
This is one night you're not turning me out.
فقط همين يه بار بذار توش بکنم عزيزم
The magic that you do
The magic that you do
You're my dream come true
You're my dream come true
My one and only you
My one and only you
Oh-oh, only you
Oh-oh, only you
Can make this change in me
Can make this change in me
For it's true
For it's true
You are my destiny
You are my destiny
When you hold my hand
When you hold my hand
I understand
I understand
The magic that you do
The magic that you do
You're my dream come true
You're my dream come true
My one
My one
And only
And only
You
You
Topper, I'm so confused. I need time alone.
تار"،الان يه کم يجم،ميخوام تنها باشم"
Admiral Benson!
"آدميرال "بنسون
Really? That's my name, too.
واقعاً..؟ اسم منم همينه که
Yankee Doodle Floppy Disk, this is Foxtrot Zulu Milkshake.
يانکي دادلي" صحبت ميکنه،اجازه فرود روي" اين اسبي که داره آهسته يورتمه ميره ميخوام
Request permission to land.
در خواست اجازه براي فرود
Roger that. You are cleared to land. Welcome to the Mediterranean.
شما ميتونين فرود بياين به درياي مديترانه خوش اومدين
Wash Out, is that you?
هي "واش"،خودتي..؟
You bet! They put me in charge of radar. I'm your eyes on the ground.
شک نکن خودمم..منو مسئول رادار اينجا کردن نترس شمام همينجان و دارم درست ميبينم
All crews report to the flight deck.
لطفاً همه خدمه به عرشه رواز همه خدمه به عرشه رواز
Have you no decency?
معلومه داري يکار ميکني؟
Ah! The open sea.
به به.. ه عظمتي
Oh, God. I wish I could smell. I had my nostrils fried in Panmunjom.
آه خدا،کاش ميتونستم بوشم استشمام کنم هري که هست بوي سرخ کردنيه
Admiral Benson!
"آدميرال "بنسون
Meet Mr Wilson and Mr Rosener of Rockman Aviation.
آقاي "ويلسون" و "راکمن" از حمل و نقل هوايي اومدن
They'll be observing the operation.
زارش عملکرد ميخوان قربان
Yes, of course.
بله،حتماً
It's OK. I'm all right. No problem.
همه ي رديفه من خوبم،مشکلي نيست
I slipped on the crab. Who put that crab there?
عين يه خرن شتک وارو ميزدين ولي تو اين دريا که خرن وجود نداره؟
- Crab? I didn't see any crab. - There were two crabs. They work in pairs.
خرن..؟ولي من فقط دوتا قورباغه مي بينم اينجا
I went to Annapolis, for Christ's sake.
يه لحظه ياد "آناوليس" افتادم
From the Pentagon, sir. We just decoded it.
از طرف نتاون قربان..رمزشايي کرديم
Help me with this. My eyes are ceramic.
يه کمکي به من بکن،شمام باباقوري ميبينه
A bazooka round at Little Bighorn. Or was it Okinawa? The one without the Indians.
يه بار يه لوله تانک خورد کنارم که موج انفجارش "داشت کورم ميکرد..در "اکيناوا
It's final orders. We strike tomorrow at 0600.
دستور نهايي رو فرستادن فردا ساعت 6 همه بايد در اعتصاب شرکت کنن
Excellent. Wake me up at, oh... 5.30.
عاليه..آخه هميشه ساعت 5:30 از خواب بيدار ميشم
- Get outta your flight suit. You're not going. - What do you mean?
برو اين کت و شلوار روازتو دربيار،ون نبايد با ما بياي منظورت يه؟
This mission is too important to let you screw it up. You're not flying.
اين يه مأموريت بسيار مهمه،دستور رسيده که جنابالي اجازه رواز نداري
- Am too. - Are not.
و منم نميذارم نه
- Oooh!
را استاد
- All right, mister. Let's go at it. - Let's do it.
بسيار خب سرکار استوار خودتو واسه جن آماده کن
Come on, come on.
بيا ديه..بيا
Whoa!
وا!
- My face! - My hand!
آي صورتم آي دستم مامان
Attention on deck!
افراد بجاي خود
Be seated.
راحت باشين
Gentlemen, we've waited a long time to hear this.
آقايون،محض اطلاعتون بايد بم که زمان زيادي به انجام عمليات نمونده
In exactly five hours and 17 minutes, we hit the enemy toast.
دقيقاً تا نج ساعت و هفده دقيقه ديه دشمن تبديل به يه نون برشته ميشه
- I think that's the enemy coast, sir. - Huh? Coast?
فکر ميکنم با دشمن در ساحل روبرو بشيم قربان ها..؟ساحل..؟
That'll take a little more planning.
اينجوري به برنامه ريزي بيشتري نياز داره
We have to knock out the nuclear-weapons plant at Falafel Heights.
در حال حاضر بايد اقدام به نابودي سلاحهاي هسته اي در ارتفاعات "فلافل" بکنيم
The plant goes on line in 12 hours and is heavily defended.
در عرض 12 ساعت اين برنامه بايد ياده بشه و ممکنه با دفاع جانانه اي روبرو بشين
If you have trouble hitting your objective,
ار که با مشکل روبرو شدين بلافاصله برين
your secondary targets are here and here:
به سراغ اهداف ثانويه در اينجا و اونجا
An accordion factory and a mime school.
يک کارخانه آکاردئون و يه مهد کودک بسيار خطرناک
Good luck, gentlemen. Blink, take over.
موفق باشين آقايون ميتونين برين
Oh, one more thing.
اوه..و يه مطلب ديه
I'll get that. It's probably for me.
ميخوام نظر شخصي خودمو بم
Our sortie will proceed as planned.
بايد بدونين که اين حمله بسيار دقيق طراحي شده
And I want Topper Harley leading our squadron into battle.
و ميخوام که "تار" فرماندهي اين حمله رو بعهده بيره
Lieutenant Commander, sir.
ببخشيد جناب فرمانده
It's nothing personal. I know I speak for every man here.
اين يه مسئله شخصي نيست،من الان دارم از جانب همه صحبت ميکنم
We've lost all respect for Harley.
هيکدوممون به "تار" اعتماد نداريم ديه
He's poison for the morale of the unit,
اون واسه واحد ما مثل يه سم مي مونه
and a disaster to the success of this mission.
براي اين مأموريت يه فاجعه بحساب مياد و
You're outta line, Gregory. You'll obey orders and like it.
"اينجا يه نفر دستور ميده "روري و بقيه موظف به اطاعت از دستوراتن
Now get to your planes.
الانم برين سراغ هوايماهاتون و آماده بشين
- Sir? - What is it, Mr Harley?
قربان..؟ يزي شده آقاي "تار"؟
- I hope I'm wrong about this. - What would that be?
اميدوارم که من انتخاب درستي باشم را همين فکري ميکني؟
Nobody likes playing for a coach who throws the big game.
اين آرزوي هرکسيه که از طرف فرمانده خودش رهبري نين عملياتي رو بيره
What's that supposed to mean?
الان ميخواي به ي برسي؟
My uncle told me that not playin' to win is like sleepin' with your sister.
عَموم هميشه ميفت که شکست در يه عمليات، درست مثل اينه که با خواهرت خوابيده باشي
Sure, she's a great piece of tail with a blouseful of goodies, but it's illegal.
حتماً يه يزي ميدونسته که اينو فته ديه ولي من خودم نين يزيو قبول ندارم
- Jesus, Topper. Come on. - Then you get into that whole inbred thing.
جون مادرت بيخيال شو "تار"،ول کن ديه اين يزا آدمو به فکر فرو ميبره
Kids with no teeth who play the banjo,
به هاي کويکي که دندون ندارن غذا بخورن و بازي کنن
eat apple sauce through a straw, pork farm animals.
نميتونن سيب زميني با سس بخورن يا وشت خوک با ني نوشابه بخورن
Topper, that's enough.
تار"،بيشتر ازين ند نزن ديه"
I think you get my point, sir.
به نظرم شما ميتونين به من اميد بدين
I just hope you're playin' straight with us.
و اميدوارم که حداقل شما با ما رو راست باشين
Alpha Velveeta Knuckle Underwear, you are cleared for takeoff.
از برج مراقبت به "آلفا"..شما آماده رواز هستين
When you hit that nuclear-weapons plant, drop a bomb for me.
زمانيکه به بالاي نيرواه هسته اي رسيدين بلافاصله بايد بمب رو رها کنين
Sphincter Mucous Niner Ringworm, roger.
"خوب شد فتي ورنه نميدونستم بايد يکار بکنم "راجر
Olé!
اوله!
Yieeee!
آي ننه!
Holy cow! My cap blew off! Swing her round. We'll pick it up.
يا او مقدس،کلاه عزيزمو باد برد نيرو اعزام کنين يداش کنن
But, sir, we're on the mission.
ولي قربان ما الان وسط يه مأموريت مهميم
Good thinking. We'll pick it up on the way back.
آفرين به تو..به نظرم موقع برشتن يداش ميکنيم
We gotta mark the spot, though. Put Rabinowitz in a life raft.
ما بايد دائم علامت ذاري کنيم که راحت بتونيم يداش کنيم
- Have him row in circles until we return. - It could be days.
ممکنه يه سفر بدون بازشت دريش داشته باشيم حتي واسه هميشه
Then put some food in the life raft, man. Do I have to think of everything?
س کاش به اندازه کافي غذا و خوراکي برداشته بوديم يعني بايد به همه ي فکر ميکردم؟
We'll tape his favourite shows.
من که نوار مورد علاقه مو برداشتم
- Sir, there's no time. - OK, OK!
قربان،زمان واسه من بي معنيه خوبه..خيلي خوبه
How can I be an admiral without my cap?
آخه مه ميشه يه آدميرال کلاه نداشته باشه؟
It's out there all alone and I'm powerless to do anything about it.
من هميشه تنها بودم و در انجام هرکاري عاجز و ناتوان
We're entering enemy airspace.
داريم وارد حريم هوايي دشمن ميشيم
Sir, it appears we have unidentified radar contacts.
قربان به نظر ميرسه ما يه تماس راداري ناشناس داشته باشيم
Looks like enemy aircraft at 12 o'clock.
فکر ميکنم هوايماهاي دشمن در موقعيت ساعت 12 باشن
Really? That gives us about... 25 minutes.
واقعاً؟حدوداً 25 دقيقه ديه مونده
Think I'll step out for a burger.
برم يه همبرر تو بزنم که خيلي ُشنمه
Sir, there are six of them! Bearing 2-1-5, range 150 mi...
قربان الان 6 مورد مشاهده شد در موقعيت5-1-2 و محدوده 150 مايلي
Oh my God, a dozen more of them.
آه خداي من،يه دوجين ديه بهشون اضافه شد که
And a blimp! A big, shiny blimp, and it's slowly moving south!
بهمراه يه بالن،يه بالن کويک يه بزر آهسته دارن به سمت جنوب ميرن
- Block, have you got a tally on the bandits? - Roger that. I got 'em.
داري به محدوده مورد نظر نزديک ميشي "بلاک"،همه آماده باشين
All right. Resume combat spread. Attack formation Delta-niner.
دريافت شد..همه آماده باشين آماده حمله به روش دلتاي نُه
Topper in the lead. Just like your old man, son.
تار"،تو الان فرمانده عملياتي..درست عين ذشته ها سر"
Old Buzz Harley'd be proud of you, Topper.
ما همه به صداي وزوز قديمت افتخار ميکنيم
He's the type that could end up killing every man in this outfit.
اون يه نيرويي که در نهايت ميتونه
He's poison for morale of the unit.
از اين کارزار سربلند بيرون بياد
Read... my... lips.
دوباره تکرار کن
No... new... taxes.
نه..همه جديدن..ي داري ميي
- Topper, what are you doing? - He's frozen! Topper's no good to us!
داري يکار ميکني "تار"؟ انار يخ زده..داري يکار ميکني؟
Abort the mission! Abort the mission!
ايان مأموريت..ايان مأموريت
Return to mother!
برميرديم به آشيانه
We can't! They're all over us!
نميتونيم..تعدادشون بيشتر از ماست
- Damn it! All right, engage! - I've got a bogie at 12 o'clock!
لعنتي..بسيار خب،درير ميشيم من "بوژ يک" در موقعيت 12 هستم
I got two on my tail! Kowalski, get 'em off me.
الان دوتا خرمس سبيدن به دم من الان منو ميزنن
Locked up! Fox two!
قفل شد "روباه دو"
My missile didn't track!
موشک به هدف نخورد
My engine's cut out. I'm losing power.
،يه موتورم کار نميکنه ضعيف کار ميکنه
My cannons won't fire! What's going on?
را موشکاي من کار نميکنه اينجا ه خبره؟
I've got two bandits on my six!
آه،دوتا از اين بزغاله ها دارن آبکشم ميکنن
This is insane. Wilson and Rosener.
همش زير سر اين عوضيه "ويلسون" با اون "روزانر"
It was them, wasn't it? They said nobody was gonna get hurt!
بهشون فته بودم که اينکارو نکنن ولي قول دادن که به کسي آسيبي نميرسه
Block, call your men back.
هي "بلاک"،به به ها بو که برردن
Like hell I will! I got the best pilot in the world up here.
شبيه به جهنم شده ولي من بهترين خلبان در دنيام
Topper! Topper, do you read me?
تار"،"تار"،صدامو ميشنوي؟"
I was there 20 years ago. I was there with your father and Mailman Farnham.
من با درت و "فارنهام" در 20 سال يش يه نين موقعيتي رو تجربه کرده بوديم
I was an eyewitness. You gotta listen to me, Topper.
خودم ديدم که يکار کردن ميشنوي ي ميم "تار"؟
What they said about your dad is wrong.
هري که تا حالا درباره درت فتن دروغ بوده سر
Eject, Mailman. Eject!
ايجکت کن سر،ايجکت کن
I can't! My seat's jammed!
نميتونم..آخه سبيدم به صندلي
- Nothing works! - Stay calm!
کمربندم کار نميکنه آروم باش سر
- My harness is malfunctioning! - I'll get it!
اين کمربند لعنتي کار نميکنه الان رديفش ميکنم
Buzz! The nose! The nose!
برو اونو بير،داره کنده ميشه
Whoa! Sit tight!
الان سِفت و محکمش ميکنم
Whoa... Whoa!
واي... واي!
Come on! Hurry!
برو ديه..زود باش
Get the lead out!
ه خرتو خريه
It's gonna be OK!
داريم ميريم ايين
Wow! That was sure close!
از اولشم بهتر شد
Buzz! Get back here!
هي..بررد بيا اينجا
Whoaaa!
واي!
Argh!
آخ!
I'm OK!
من خوبم يزي نيست
Buzz! The wing! The wing!
آي..بال سمت راست،داره جِر ميخوره
Hurry!
عجله کن
What, are you on a break?
برو سر،تو ميتوني
- Hurry! - I'm here!
زود باش من همينجام
Hey, whose gum is this? Whoa!
هي،آدامس اينجا يکار ميکنه؟
Oh, for God's sake! Not now!
اوه،جون مادرت عين آدم بشين
Got it! Hold on! We'll bring this baby down!
کجا ميري!!..صبر کن ديه دارم از وسط دوتا ميشم
Stop squirming!
خودم مي يرمت سر
Hang on!
دارم جِر ميخورم
- Whoa! - Those are my socks!
اي ريدم به اين جوراباي تُخميت
Buzz! Get back here!
هي..منو اينجا تنها نذار
Your father did everything possible to save Mailman's life.
درت مثل يه انسان واقعي تا لحظه آخر واسه نجات جونش تلاش کرد
You should be proud, son. Buzz Harley is a true American hero.
تو بايد به درت افتخار کني "اون يه قهرمان واقعي بود "تار
- I'm hit! I'm hit! - Block, are you all right?
من تير خوردم..زخمي شدم بلاک"،همه ي رديفه؟"
Yes! Yes!
آره..آره
Give 'em hell!
الان واسشون جهنم به ا ميکنم
Got it! This is for you, Dad.
ادامه بده..فقط بخاطر تو در
- They're on my tail. - I'm with you, buddy.
دوباره سبيدن به من نترس من نميذارم توش بکنن رفيق
Hang in there.
خودتو جدا کن
My guns are jammed.
موشک منم کار نميکنه
They got tone on me!
الان خواهرمادرشونو سرويس ميکنم
I'm gonna have to do it the hard way.
ميخوام اون روي کلفت خودمو بهشون نشون بدم
Anybody home?
برين يش مامان جونتون
They fell for that one.
يه حال اساسي بهشون دادم
- Topper! Three bandits, 12 o'clock! - I'm on 'em!
تار"،سه تا ديه سبيدن به من" خودم دارمشون
Here we go, loop de loop.
را اينقدر کُس رخ ميزنن
Couscous!
"هي "کوسکوس
Learned this one from Paula Abdul.
حالا واستون نمايش "ائولا عبدل" رو ياده ميکنم
Oldest trick in the book.
رسماً مادرشون اييده شد
Catch me if you can, guys. Here's an old Buzz Harley move.
الان يه حال ديه بهشون ميدم اين يکي از ترفنداي "تار" بزر بود
- Oh, boys... - Agh!
سلام به ها آخ!
I'm on their tails. I've got 'em now.
الان شت سرشونم الان در تيررس منن
Hey, buddy.
طوري خوشل سر
It looks like they're buggin' out.
فکر ميکنم دارن از هم جدا ميشن
Yikes!
!!..اوه
Saved by the clouds. Come on in, boys.
به ها حالا برين داخل اين همه ابر حال کنين
A little hide-and-seek.
الان فقط يه کم مخفي شدم به ها
See ya later, guys.
به اميد ديدار به ها
This could be the end of a beautiful friendship.
حيف که اين دوستيمون داره خيلي زود تموم ميشه
Topper, look out!
هي "تار" مواظب باش
I got two heat-seeking missiles on my tail.
مي بينم که دوتا موشک سفارشيم واسم فرستادن
Block, Kent, Kowalski, get the hell outta here.
بلاک"،"کنت"،"کوالسکي..واسه يه جهنم آماده باشين"
Get back to the ship! I got me a nuclear-weapons plant to wax.
شما ميتونين برردين به کشتي من ميخوام اين موشکارو ببرم سمت يه نيرواه هسته اي
- You're committing suicide! - Do as he says!
به اين مين خودکشي سر من که نميفهمم ي داره ميه
We are getting close.
داريم نزديک ميشيم
Missiles? Still with me. Come on.
موشک ي شد؟ همنان شت سرم ميان
If I can't lose 'em, I'll use 'em.
نميخوام از دستشون بدم بايد ازشون استفاده کنم
The mother of all targets.
هدف اصلي رؤيت شد
Sayonara, Saddam.
باي باي جناب صدام
Come in! Are you all right? Topper, acknowledge!
بجُنب سر..حالت خوبه؟ "يه يزي بو "تار
- Topper, do you read? - Topper, are you all right?
صدامو ميشنوي "تار"؟ حالت خوبه؟
There they are!
بالاخره اومدن
Uh, we're landing. Get out of the way.
من بايد فرود بيام اجازه فرود ميخوام
Run for your lives!
هرکي جونشو دوست داره فرار کنه
- Where's Topper? - Lost contact.
س "تار" کجاست؟ هنوز تماس نرفته
- There he is! - Pyrex Pickle Blowfish.
ديدمش..داره مياد تبديل به يه شيشه ترشي شدم
Permission to land.
اجازه فرود ميخوام
You'll have to talk me down. I've got damage.
اه ميتوني با من حرف بزن من زخمي شدم..
Hold it, hold it!
هي ساکت باشين،همه ساکت
OK, Topper. Ease her in.
باشه "تار"،نترس يزي نيست.
- Landing gear's frozen. - Lookin' good.
اهرم لندين کار نميکنه بازم سعي کن
- Lost my radar. - A little more power now.
رادار ندارم ديه بازم ميتوني رواز کني
- I'm out of fuel. - Right for lineup.
آره هنوز سوخت دارم س بايد آماده فرود بشي ديه
- Lost a wing. - Doin' fine.
ولي يه بال ندارم اين که خيلي خوبه سر
- There goes the other one. - OK, Topper. Call the ball.
ولي با همين يکي ميشينم عاليه "تار"،حالا کجايي
Touchin' down.
الان مثه ِشل ميخورم زمين
Wha-hoo!
هوراااا!
Well done, Jim!
"دمت رم "جيم
- You're quite a guy! - So are you!
به تو مين يه مرد همنين به تو خوشله
Hey! Wash Out!
"هي.."واش
Oh, Topper...
"اوه،"تار
You.
فقط تو
- I got one question for you. - Shoot.
ميخوام ازت يه يزي برسم برس
What is a chafing dish for?
اون ظرف غذارو ميخواستي يکار؟
Why, it's a traditional serving piece used at brunches to keep food warm.
اون يه ظرف غذاي سنتي واسه رم نهداشتن غذاست..همين
- I thought that was a Crockpot. - No, no, no.
فکر ميکردم مثه يه زودز کار ميکنه نه..نه..نه
That's for cooking all day. A chafing dish...
يعني يه جورايي هميشه غذارو رم نه ميداره
Hey, Topper! Now that you've made the world safe for democracy,
هي "تار"،حالا که در راه دمکراسي يه قدم ..بزري برداشتي
what will you do to cash in on your new-found fame?
اه ولدار بشي باهاش يکار ميکني تا دوباره مشهور بشي؟
I'm goin' to Disneyland!
"ميرم به "ديزني لند
You're very fortunate, Commander Block. This man has your blood type.
واقعاً خوش شانس بودين فرمانده "بلاک" که روه خوني اين مرد با شما يکيه
Don't worry, sir. After this transfusion, you're gonna be just fine.
نران نباشين قربان،بعد از اين انتقال حالتون از اولشم بهتر ميشه
I've only seen heroism like that one other time.
من فقط داشتم به اين دلاوري و شجاعت تو ناه ميکردم
Maybe you know the pilot: Leland "Buzz" Harley.
شايد به ظاهر "ليلاند" و "تار" بزرو بشناسي
I've been carrying this secret around for 20 years.
ولي در مدت اين 20 سال همه ي رو مخفي نهداشتم
I never spoke up.
هيوقت يزي نفتم
I wanted him to fail.
هميشه ميخواستم شکست بخوره
I wanted to be number one.
خودم ميخواستم هميشه اول باشم
And I was in love with your mother.
ون من عاشق مادرت بودم
It's not important now, sir. Please, save your strength for your court martial.
الان اصلاً مهم نيست قربان لطفاً بيشتر از اين حرف نزنين که واستون خوب نيست
Topper, you had me pegged right.
تار"،تو هميشه خودتو به من ثابت کردي"
I was throwin' the big game.
دست به يه قمار بزر زدم
Oh!
اوه!
I really thought we needed that other airplane.
من واقعاً اعتقاد داشتم که بايد ناوان هوايي جديد و نو بشه
But now I realise that American planes'll always be superior
ولي الانم باور دارم که آمريکا هميشه برتر از همه ست
as long as there are wonderful men like you in the cockpit
البته تا زمانيکه مردان قهرماني مثل ..تو داشته باشيم و
and German parts.
اون قطعات و لوازم يدکي آلماني نباشه
I know you think it was me, but it was Wilson and Rosener who sabotaged the jets.
من ميدونستم که ممکنه فکر کني کار منه ولي همه اين مسائل زير سر "ويلسون" بود
They played me like a two-bit piccolo.
هردوشون دائم منو تهديد ميکردن
Oh! Oh...
اوه! اوه...
Whoaaaaa!
واي ي ي ي !
I can see my house from here!
از اينجا خونمونم ديده ميشه که
Oh no, you don't.
اوه،بايد يه حال تو بهت بدم
- Admiral! - You call yourself an American?
آدميرال؟ شما خودتونو يه آمريکايي ميدونين؟
That gets my panties in a bunch. It's scum like you that taint our military.
تو مثه يه شورت اه داري که دائم خودتو اي اينو اون ميکني،لکه نن
You don't know what you're talking about.
تو حق نداري با من اينجوري حرف بزني
You risked the lives of some fine pilots.
جون کلي آدمو به خطر انداختي
Well, that's my job.
خب،اين کارمه ديه
Is it safe?
اصلاً ترس نداره
You look good up there, son.
ناه خوب داشته باش سر
I think I'm wearing your pants.
احساسم الان مثه وقت شلوار وشيدنمه
- Ramada! - Kent!
"راماندا" "کنت"
- You're OK. - Ramada.
حالت خوبه؟ "راماندا"
You must put me out of your mind.
تو بايد منو ديه فراموش کني
There's a certain flyboy aboard that ship that needs you far more than I.
يه خلبان ديه هست که خيلي احساس نزديکتري از بقيه به من داره
- You must forget me. - No problem. I will.
بايد منو فراموش کني باشه مشکلي نيست
Please... Not a tear.
خواهشاً ريه نکن ديه
Don't look back. That's my brave girl.
را برنميردي تو دختر واقعاً شجاعي هستي
Don't worry, little one! As long as I have me, I'll survive!
نران نباش،زود ميذره تا زمانيکه زنده ام به يادتم
Aarghhh!
واي  ي ي ي ي!
Topper!
"تار"
Go, Bill, go!
برو "بيل"..برو ديه
Wait!
صبر کن
Whoa!
وايسا
Topper!
"تار"
Ramada.
"رامادا"
Once, perhaps. Now I'm called Wawatukeena.
يه زماني شايد..ولي الان دست ر اومدم
- What does it mean? - Little Sizzling Belly.
منظورت يه؟ واسه سرخ کردن ديه
Every night I hope and pray
Every night I hope and pray
A dream lover will come my way
A dream lover will come my way
A girl to hold in my arms
A girl to hold in my arms
And know the magic of her charms
And know the magic of her charms
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- A girl
- A girl
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
I want a dream lover
I want a dream lover
I don't have to dream alone
I don't have to dream alone
Dream lover, where are you
Dream lover, where are you
With a love, oh, so true?
With a love, oh, so true?
And a hand that I can hold
And a hand that I can hold
To feel you near as I grow old?
To feel you near as I grow old?
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- A girl
- A girl
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
I want a dream lover
I want a dream lover
I don't have to dream alone
I don't have to dream alone
Some day, I don't know how
Some day, I don't know how
I know she'll hear my plea
I know she'll hear my plea
Some way, I don't know how
Some way, I don't know how
She'll bring her love to me
She'll bring her love to me
Dream lover, until then
Dream lover, until then
I'll go to sleep, I'll dream again
I'll go to sleep, I'll dream again
That's the only thing to do
That's the only thing to do
Till all my lover's dreams come true
Till all my lover's dreams come true
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- A girl
- A girl
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
I want a dream lover
I want a dream lover
I don't have to dream alone
I don't have to dream alone
Dream lover, until then
Dream lover, until then
I'll go to sleep, I'll dream again
I'll go to sleep, I'll dream again
That's the only thing to do
That's the only thing to do
Till all my lover's dreams come true
Till all my lover's dreams come true
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- Because I want - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- A girl
- A girl
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- To call - Yeah-yeah, yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
- My own - Yeah-yeah
I want a dream lover
I want a dream lover
I don't have to dream alone
I don't have to dream alone
Please don't make me dream alone
Please don't make me dream alone
Don't make me
Don't make me